MAHMUD DEMILADE AKINBAMI

KENT, UNITED KINGDOM

My Email +447778791263

Portfolio

Professional Summary

Studied product design at the University of Greenwich, with a background of Engineering and natural skills in User experience and User Interface design (UI/UX). Proficient in Figma, HTML,CSS and JavaScript. Demonstrated success in user centred design and great skills in collaboration with other people and a keen eye in Diversity and Inclusion whilst having multiple certificates in UX design courses and Web Development courses.

Experience

Sales Supervisor | Marks and Spencer

Kent, United Kingdom | January 2024 till date

Job Summary:

- Ensured stocks are accurate and not of date by creating a routine checkup which is 100% effective.
- Created a system which reduced daily food waste by 83%
- Lead the shift daily including opening and closing procedures, as well as inventory management and making critical decisions.
- Responsible for finding out stock gap and monitoring and reporting sales performance.

Sales Assistant | Marks and Spencer

Kent, United Kingdom | November 2023 till January 2024

Job Summary:

- Engaged with customers in a friendly and professional manner.
- Provided product information, demonstrations and recommendations to customers based on their requirements.

Product Designer | Group project

Lagos, Nigeria | 2023

Key Achievement: Improved the user experience and increase user engagement of a free invoice generator <u>website</u>.

My contribution to the project were;

- Created the Logo.
- Designed the website's header using atomic design system.

Field Technician/Web designer | Skaap Consult

Lagos, Nigeria | March 2022 till August 2023

Job Summary:

- Created over 80 technical reports and provided technical advice to clients.
- Created and managed the company's website whilst working with the company.

Intern | Mikano Construction

Lagos, Nigeria | May 2020 till July 2020

Job Summary:

 Overseeing a variety of engineering projects including casting and ensuring projects are completed to time, budget, and customer requirements.

Clerk | Lagos State University Teaching Hospital

Lagos, Nigeria | December 2017 till January 2018

Job Summary:

• Ensuring the efficient administration of the Haematology department including completing routine and ad hoc administrative duties.

Education

Msc Product Design | University of Greenwich

London, United Kingdom | September 2023 till September 2024.

BSc Engineering | University of Ibadan

Oyo, Nigeria | Graduated December 2021.

Certificates

- Google's certificate of Foundations of User Experience Design.
- Lighthall training Platform: Product Design.
- Google's Certificate of Design to Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes.
- Future Learn Digital Skills: User Experience.
- Google's Certificate of Design to start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate.
- Dev and Design JavaScript.

Skills

- Design Tools: Figma, Web flow, WordPress, Wix
- Software: Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Google Sheet,
- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Design: User Research, UI/UX, Wireframing, Prototyping, Design Systems, Information architecture, Diversity and inclusivity design, Interaction design, Usability testing, Atomic Design, Visual design, Typography, Colour theory, Design systems, Responsive design, Mobile app design, Web design, Persona creation, Customer journey mapping, Interaction Design.
- Communication: Collaborative Design, Design Sprints
- Marketing: SEO

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE ON REQUESTS.